It's just that…
I can't have sex.
What?
Yeah.
It's a problem I have,
and I wanted to tell you that.
I like you a lot, Yumi.
Would you
go out with me again?
Whoa.
I thought you weren't into me.
So I'm relieved that's not what it is.
Mmm.
But…
When you…
When you say that you can't…
What is it?
That's a bit…
Uh, you…
If you can't be honest,
what am I supposed to think
about any of this?
Yeah, you're right.
You know…
Hey, uh, you're that reporter, aren't you?
Uh…
Yeah, that's me.
Uh, I'm sorry…
- Can I shake your hand? I'm a big fan.
- Mm-hm.
- Thank you very much.
- Thanks. I didn't mean to interrupt.
Do you…
mind if I take a few moments with this?
I'm sorry.
I understand.
WATCH YOUR SURROUNDINGS!
STOP VOYEURISM
What about "Top 10 Face-in-the-Hole
Photo Boards Across Japan"?
Ooh!
That's fun. We'd have Miku going around
the country visiting different ones.
Or maybe we play it safe.
"Best Ramen Places in All of Japan."
- That works.
- Not sure. We did ramen last week.
We could spotlight new places?
- Hm, let's think… Local craft beer.
- Beer's good.
- And go!
- I'm good with that.
- Find out everything you can.
- Uh?
I thought we could do
a feature on voyeurism?
Yumi… you did hear us debating
between ramen and beer stories?
- Right?
- Of course, but…
Those posters you see around town?
It feels to me like it's putting
the burden on the victims.
I thought they were
becoming less common.
- But I saw another one today.
- Hm.
It gets women thinking
that no matter what,
someone could be filming them,
or that maybe they're not safe
anywhere they go nowadays.
- I think it's something to consider.
- When you say "women"?
Are you talking specifically
about yourself, or all of you?
Should we ask
the other women in this room too?
- Yeah, not sure I totally…
- Uh, I don't know.
- I mean…
- I think it's a good idea.
We did that feature when
they passed that law criminalizing
unauthorized filming, right?
So maybe we approach it from the angle
of seeing if anything's changed
since it was enacted.
It would be interesting to see
whether the law's made
any kind of difference at all, right?
Not a bad idea.
Mitarai, why don't you
get to work on a proposal,
and we'll see if there's a story here.
- I can do that, no problem.
- Good.
Thank you very much.
In the interest
of efficiency with timelines,
let's keep working
on the beer story as well.
- Yes, sir.
- Sound good?
Here are your main courses.
Sorry for the wait.
Hey, I wanted to say thanks
for stepping in earlier.
No need to thank me, I just thought
it was a story worth telling.
And also,
I'm really sorry about the other day.
For canceling on you.
It's all good.
You can have lunch with me right now.
Refills are complimentary,
so go ahead and help yourself.
- Here.
- Ah. Thank you very much.
I've wanted to discuss
something with you.
You know,
back when I was training you,
it felt like I heard a lot
on your goals and dreams with this job.
But now I don't.
Honestly, were you thinking
about quitting?
Huh?
Come on, tell me.
Were you thinking about quitting the show
or being a reporter altogether?
A bit. You're not wrong.
Mmm. There was a vibe, I could feel it.
Hmm.
Today was good, though. It felt like
you got your groove back in there.
You'll be okay.
We all go through periods like that.
Yeah.
I'm potty trained, ready to be a big girl,
and take on the world.
Hmm. That's good to hear.
Hi, there, I've got
an order here for shanrāton?
- Yup.
- Please. Here you go.
Enjoy.
Mmm.
But I'm touched
that you cared enough
to notice I was off, Shun.
Huh.
Well, of course I care.
Because people care
for the things that are…
that are important.
So, today,
we're gonna do a little exercise.
Until the sand runs out of the timer,
I want you to say
whatever words come to mind,
without worrying
if they make any sense or not.
- Words?
- Yes.
By putting these
fragmented memories into words,
little by little,
the trauma will begin to organize.
Our eventual goal is for you
to be able to describe, in your own words,
exactly what happened.
Then we hope that, even in situations
where your body used to panic or react,
that you'll be able
to remain calm and grounded.
Smell.
Night.
Sound.
Beer can.
Bed.
Laughter.
Fingertips.
Stop.
Cigarettes.
Shower.
Festival.
Lanterns.
My father's voice.
A home I don't recognize.
Arched brown windows.
Skin.
Glass.
A hammer.
Someone says, "Stop."
Blood.
Scalpel.
HARMONIA LAW OFFICE
ATTORNEY
I'm Kiyoshi Kanie, his attorney.
You were arrested for voyeuristic filming?
Yes.
We reached a settlement with the victim.
They're not pressing charges.
Under the condition
that my client undergoes treatment
to prevent reoffending.
I regret my actions.
I swear I'll never do it again.
You used your smartphone to film it?
Yeah.
Here.
My wife smashed it
after everything happened.
So I wouldn't do it again.
For the sake of their child,
who, for the moment,
knows nothing of what happened,
they're gonna try to save the marriage.
I'm begging you to make me better,
to help save my family!
Please, doctor!
You have to help me find a way.
Ugh! Ugh!
Oh my goodness, it's so gross! Ugh!
Ooh.
What do these voyeur creeps get out
of filming people? I don't understand!
Plus the guy's got
a whole family waiting at home.
No wonder he's
so desperate to figure this out.
It's funny, I always pictured
guys who do this
being creepy and unpopular, you know?
Roughly half the confirmed perpetrators
of voyeuristic filming are college grads.
They also say half are company employees.
Not only that, 40% of them have spouses.
Do you know what that tells us?
It tells us they're just ordinary people?
Yeah, everyday people, just like
the three of us sitting here.
And a good chunk of them
don't even use the material afterwards.
Then why do they do it?
Masturbation.
Some don't even watch it.
They delete it right after.
Just… What's the point, then?
It's similar to groping.
About half don't even get aroused
during the actual assault.
Basically, the voyeuristic
photography or groping
isn't actually the thing
that satisfies them sexually.
Huh?
Oh! Well, then,
I really don't get the point of it.
Ugh, ugh, ugh, I just don't get it!
Aah, aah, aah!
- Ugh!
- Hold on! Is that supposed to be me?
Hey, Yuta, quick question.
What are you doing
on your day off tomorrow?
Tomorrow? I don't think
I have anything going on.
Hold on. You better not be thinking
of using me as bait for voyeur perverts!
- Don't be ridiculous.
- Good. 'Cause that would be harassment.
Of course it would.
- So, what is it?
- You'll see.
Wait, what the heck is this?
I had Marin film a day in your life, Yuta.
Breathtaking stuff.
Wait, hold on a second, what did you do?
- I apologize.
- Yeah, sorry.
What the…
Oh, you were there the whole time?
- I didn't notice?
- How was it? Not too bad?
Well, it was a little
nerve-wracking, to be honest.
All these thoughts
were coming into my head.
"Is this a good shot?"
or "Will I get caught?"
It was pretty stressful, but
I got it done without him noticing me.
- So I was relieved.
- So, there you go. That's what it is.
That cycle that goes
between stress and release.
- That's what they crave.
- Oh!
- I think I understand it more.
- Hmm.
It's like when I was young,
and I would play
hide-and-seek with my friends.
I'd get a rush watching
the seeker run around
while I was trying not be found.
It was a real rush.
At their core, these people
desire control or superiority.
They get off watching someone
without them knowing.
Huh.
Oh, like how I felt when I got this shot?
Ohh!
No! No! Stop! No! Delete it now!
Relax! I didn't print it, out of mercy.
- I'm begging you, please delete that.
- Okay, okay, my bad!
This is messed up.
Like, seriously, it's nuts.
The thought of someone taking pictures
of me makes me not wanna leave my home.
Well, that's the thing that threatens
people's sense of security every day.
Voyeurism.
If I'm being completely honest,
I don't think
I was taking it seriously enough.
You know, just the thought of
someone doing that to my girlfriend?
I'd never get over it.
The other day, Toshiyuki was on his knees,
begging for help
to keep his family together.
And you felt for the guy, didn't you?
But look, treating him is only the start.
We can help more victims
by preventing voyeurs
from indulging in harmful practices.
Whenever I try to get on a train,
I suddenly feel like I can't breathe,
like my chest is constricted.
So I decided to transfer
to a school I could walk to.
But then I started to worry that there
might be photos of me online somewhere.
It got so bad, I was afraid
of going on the Internet at all.
Eventually, it got to the point where
I was terrified to even look at my phone.
Has this fear impacted
your daily life at all?
Hmm.
Totally. It's so bad,
I can't even leave my home anymore.
- I'm just too scared.
- Um, I…
You should know, sir,
after completing these interviews?
- I believe this is a story worth doing.
- I always felt someone was near, watching.
- Hmm.
- Carrying that dread all the time is hard.
So he thinks
the victim's perspective feels too dark.
Are you surprised?
That does sound like
something your producer would say.
If the victim's perspective
is too dark, it's not their fault!
I don't get it!
What did he expect from her?
Anyway, I'm really sorry
to rant about all of this.
I'm sure it's annoying.
No, that's what I'm here for.
Oh, and if that proposal goes through,
please let me know?
I'm gonna get it approved.
No matter what.
You know, getting that invested is…
Yeah.
But it's not… just that, it's…
I was a victim too.
Send it, send it, send it!
- Come on, come on, come on!
- Dude, you're crazy!
- Do it, bro! Send it!
- You idiot!
- Yo, I got it!
- That's insane.
Whoa! I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
Even back then…
…he…
…never asked me anything,
he just stayed with me.
Why would he?
Why couldn't I have just been patient?
Waited till he was ready?
Do you remember the first time
you engaged in this sort of activity?
I do, yes.
It was my first year of college.
I was sitting
on the stairs at the station,
and I happened to see
under a woman's skirt.
I was so shocked
that it kinda took my breath away.
All my fatigue from school
just sort of melted away.
I wanted that to happen again.
It felt like a waste,
never to chase that feeling I had.
My flip phone was all I needed.
And after I did that, well…
I started doing it whenever
I got tired from doing schoolwork.
Then you claim the first time
you were caught was in your senior year.
Yeah. So, that time,
I was on an escalator.
An attendant saw me.
But 'cause I was a senior
looking for a job, I…
Well, my lawyer negotiated and
asked them not to ruin my entire future.
So I paid a settlement
and wasn't prosecuted.
After that, there were periods
when it went away completely.
But slowly, with the stress from work,
and how easy smartphones make it
to take clear pictures these days…
Oh, uh…
How many times do you think
you've done this, roughly?
Uh…
I don't know,
I don't really keep count of it.
Uh…
I'd say roughly two or three times a week?
And if you exclude the periods
when I stopped completely,
it's been around 15 years.
2,160.
And even after doing it that many times,
this is only, what,
the second time you've been caught?
Yeah.
Only this time,
I don't know, I felt like
she wanted me to take her picture.
I mean, she walked up
and stood right in front of me.
I got the sense that
she realized what was happening,
and she didn't seem bothered by it.
Some girls don't mind
being photographed like that.
It would appear,
in this case, the subway station acts
as a sort of trigger for you.
Do you think, at least for now,
you could adjust your daily routine
to avoid subway stations completely?
Maybe try commuting by car?
Oh.
Yes.
I can, for sure.
Okay, let's begin there.
This is my assignment for you to complete.
Keep a detailed record of how you feel
each day until our next session.
If you got through the day
without much trouble, use the blue one.
If you struggled with your new routine,
or felt it was difficult,
use a yellow sticker.
If it felt really hard and you could feel
yourself really wanting to do it again,
use the red.
The most important thing is honesty.
That's all I ask.
All right.
So he thought
she wanted her picture taken, huh?
Hm. Definition
of cognitive distortion to me.
Yeah.
Yeah, with groping, it's the same.
People take someone who's frozen in terror
and try to convince themselves
it's them wanting it,
since they aren't actively resisting.
How can someone
possibly truly believe that?
He knows he has to stop.
But for some reason, he can't.
Given that most people can't stand
that contradiction, he justifies it. Hmm.
Also there might be some
deep-seated male chauvinistic idea
that women are just supposed
to accept men's lust,
no matter how much they don't want it.
You know, as if women
are objects and not people.
He told you that he only takes pictures
under the women's skirts, right?
So he picks his targets
based on their wardrobe,
he doesn't photograph their faces.
And that further proves
he's not seeing them as women at all.
Ugh! What should we do about this?
Well, first and foremost,
we need to correct that perception,
or there's no point
in even starting his treatment.
YUMI ICHINOSE
Hey, take it if you need to.
Uh, no, it's okay.
- I actually wanted to ask you--
- This is delicious, by the way.
I told you.
Professor, you never
told me you could cook.
Thinking older men don't know
how to cook is also cognitive distortion.
Isn't that just straight-up prejudice?
Yes, that's right.
But in fairness, I do spend
a lot of time with young students,
so, naturally, I pick up
a lot of this from them.
- Oh! Which of this is your favorite?
- Oh.
I am actually gonna return this call.
I want to apologize for the other day.
I shouldn't have pushed you
to say something
you weren't ready to share yet.
Do you, uh,
remember in middle school
when I had that voyeur thing happen?
When all that stuff went down,
you didn't force me to say anything.
You just sat by my side.
You told me not to talk till I was ready.
That whether something happened or not,
that you would just sit and listen.
That was so selfless.
So I want you know that I'll wait too.
No matter how long it takes
for you to feel comfortable with me.
Thank you.
I'm actually
treating someone who's addicted
to voyeuristic filming right now.
Small world.
I thought of what you went through
back in the day.
I don't want anyone else
to go through what you went through.
No one deserves that.
But it's odd.
He has no clue that
there are real victims to his actions.
He doesn't understand how hurt
people are by what he's done.
I don't know what to do, to be honest.
Well, maybe you could
try… letting him hear
from all the people he's hurt?
Could that be an option?
FACT-FINDING RECORD
ON STAFF CONDUCT
July 31st, Arakawa Station.
Mr. Ikeuchi, you were arrested
for voyeuristic filming?
Huh?
Someone from the company
happened to be on the scene.
It's become a big rumor.
I was.
In that case, we'd ask you not come in
while we consider disciplinary options.
You did the right thing
by calling me here.
But… I don't care anymore.
What's the point
of me doing any treatment?
Without the pictures,
it's as if
I lost my reason to live entirely.
Well, that's just the addiction talking.
But you…
you were able to ask me for help
when you were in need.
That's huge, and why I really meant it
when I thanked you for calling me.
Good for you.
It shows, somewhere deep inside,
that you don't want to be doing this.
Your prescription is ready.
I won't lie to you.
This is not gonna be an easy experience.
Are you ready to get better?
Yes.
Help me, please.
You let me know any time you need a break.
Thanks.
Sir, I want to thank you for agreeing
to do this interview with me today.
Of course.
Now, I'd like to begin.
I see.
I told my family that I lost my job.
So my main focus is to quit
taking these photos once and for all.
I'm ready.
I understand
you're going through treatment?
Yes, for the last little while.
Thank you for opening up.
One other thing before we wrap this up.
Would you like to see the footage
we mentioned to you before?
Yes.
I would, please.
All right.
These are from people
who heard we were speaking to you.
They wanted to share their stories
of being victims of these actions.
So we filmed them for this exact moment.
Just to confirm before we begin,
do you consent to having your face shown?
Yes.
That's very brave. Thank you.
Would you be all right showing your face?
Of course.
Thank you very much.
Don't feel obligated
to say anything you don't want to.
In your own words,
would you tell us about
the time you were victimized?
Well, I was filmed
when I was on the subway.
And even now…
…I find myself scared to get back on.
Not just the train, either.
Crowded places in town, anywhere.
But when I see a train go by,
I automatically revert back
to that moment in time.
And suddenly, it's like I'm paralyzed.
Last year,
I went to an open-air bath with my family.
And… I saw this…
man standing there.
And it just hit me.
It doesn't matter how old you are,
you can be still be
the victim of something like this.
I also couldn't stop
thinking about my daughter.
I was filmed in the locker room
and bathroom of the office I work at.
The next thing I knew,
the videos were put online.
Now, whenever a man comes near me,
I'm terrified he might secretly
film me again.
Or, at least, he may be
looking at photos of me online.
I find it hard to leave the house at all.
So it's been rough.
These days, the only time
I ever really go out
is to go to the hospital
to get medication.
Is there anything you'd like to say
to the men who do this kind of thing
and are currently watching this video?
I think I'd just like to know, why me?
What did I do?
Did I do something wrong?
What was it?
What did I do to deserve this?
Is it just because I'm a woman?
I also have something to say to you.
I was a victim of
voyeuristic filming as well.
- Guys, it's so bad.
- Send it!
Back when I was in middle school,
the boys in my class
took a photo of me and sent it around.
Send them.
Of course, that was already bad enough,
but that wasn't it.
Boys this age are starting puberty
and be can real idiots, you know?
But the truth is,
they're just stressed with entrance exams.
Can you let this go?
Oh, come on, it's nothing!
Think about it as a compliment, in a way.
You're basically the most beautiful girl
in class to these guys.
I was extremely shocked and hurt
that these guys got off
without any punishment.
And let's be fair, Yumi.
Your skirt is shorter
than school regulation stipulates.
You're basically
asking these boys to take photos.
It was the first time I felt…
I'll warn them…
…both my dignity and voice
being taken from me at the same time.
Just like the rest of those women.
It's important for you,
and all perpetrators, to know
that each victim of voyeuristic filming
has a face and a voice.
We are human beings,
with full and meaningful lives.
I only hope
you'll never forget that.
I'm so sorry.
Please forgive me.
So, what do you think? Can he really quit?
There's no complete cure
for any addiction.
What?
All you can do is face
the consequences of your actions
and keep making an effort to be better
every second for the rest of your days.
So what you
really mean is that
there's no such thing as quitting.
Well, you stack up the days
where you manage not to do it.
And slowly, it gets easier
over time, you know?
Or that's the hope.
You know what I realized?
I've had my voice
robbed from me twice now.
The first time, of course, in school.
And by the network,
when they made me do the weather.
I wanted to be a reporter,
but they convinced me
to do the weather anyway.
But today, I was proud.
I spoke with my own voice,
using my own words.
And finally, for the first time
in I don't know how long,
I felt like the reporter
I was meant to be.
Hmm.
So, now we get this project approved!
About the other day?
I'm sorry.
I know I said I'd be patient
and wait until you were ready,
but I did want to ask just one thing.
Mmm.
When you said you couldn't do it…
did you mean just right now?
Mmm.
Okay.
Glad to hear it.
I…
I really like you, Ichito.
I guess what I'm saying is
the answer is yes.
That's good.
So, then…
A-ha!
They look like they're having fun.
Don't look at me, don't look at me.